Hi there, and welcome back.
Jos: Hola, y bienvenido.
In this video, we're going to look at Booleans.
En este video, vamos a ver Booleanos.
A Boolean is a specific type of data,
Un booleano es un tipo especfico de
just like numbers and strings, and the name comes
datos, al igual que los nmeros y las cadenas, y
from the person who invented it,
el nombre proviene de la persona
a guy called George Boole, who was a mathematician.
que lo invent, un tipo llamado George Boole, que era matemtico.
A Boolean is a value that represents two possible states.
Un booleano es un valor que representa dos estados posibles.
Frequently, those are true and false,
Con frecuencia, esos son verdaderos y falsos,
but they can also be things like yes or no,
pero tambin pueden ser cosas como s
one and zero, and things like that.
o no, uno y cero, y cosas por el estilo.
In Python, Booleans can be true, or they can be false.
En Python, los booleanos pueden ser verdaderos, o pueden ser falsos.
And we use them of course to make decisions.
Y los usamos, por supuesto, para tomar decisiones.
For example, we can ask if something is true,
Por ejemplo, podemos preguntar si algo es cierto, luego vamos a
then we're gonna do this, and if this is false,
hacer esto, y si esto es falso, entonces vamos a
then we're gonna do that, and so on.
hacer eso, y as sucesivamente.
It allows our programmes to do things depending on something.
Permite a nuestros programas hacer cosas dependiendo de algo.
So, we're gonna start by defining a couple of variables
Entonces, comenzaremos por definir un par
that represent these true and false values.
de variables que representen estos valores verdaderos y falsos.
I'm gonna call the variable truthy,
Voy a llamar verdad a
because its value is one that will be true.
la variable, porque su valor es uno que ser verdadero.
And indeed, this value here is the definition
Y de hecho, este valor aqu es la
of true in Python, True with a capital T.
definicin de verdadero en Python, verdadero con mayscula T.
As you can see, it goes blue, because Python recognises it
Como puede ver, se vuelve azul, porque Python lo reconoce
as a keyword, and this is one of these
como una palabra clave, y este es uno de los
that you shouldn't name your variables after.
que no debe nombrar sus variables despus.
So don't name your variables True with a capital T.
As que no nombre sus variables True con mayscula T.
That's a recipe for disaster.
Esa es una receta para el desastre.
But the variable is called truthy
Pero la variable se llama truthy
because it represents a value that is true.
porque representa un valor que es verdadero.
Similarly, we could create a variable called falsy
Del mismo modo, podramos crear una variable llamada falsy y
and make it False, again, with a capital F.
hacerla False, de nuevo, con una F. mayscula.
Remember the names of the variables are,
Recuerde que los nombres de las variables son,
don't matter at all.
no importan en absoluto.
They are just names for these values.
Solo son nombres para estos valores.
And so you could name them whatever you want.
Y entonces puedes ponerles el nombre que quieras.
But the concept of truthy and falsy values is important,
Pero el concepto de valores de falsedad y falsedad es
as we'll come to see later on.
importante, como veremos ms adelante.
Instead of only using true and false,
En lugar de solo usar verdadero
we can also calculate whether something is true or false.
y falso, tambin podemos calcular si algo es verdadero o falso.
For example, let's say we have a variable called age,
Por ejemplo, digamos que tenemos una variable llamada edad, y
and that's equal to 20.
eso equivale a 20.
We can calculate whether the age is over and equal to 18.
Podemos calcular si la edad es mayor o igual a 18.
For example, let's create another variable,
Por ejemplo, creemos otra
called it is_over_age, and we're gonna make it
variable, llamada is_over_age, y
equal to age &gt;= 18.
la igualaremos a age> = 18.
Now, again, this single equals side is key
Ahora, de nuevo, este lado igual nico es
in this expression, because whatever is behind it,
clave en esta expresin, porque todo lo que est detrs, lo
whatever is to the right, is going to get calculated first
que sea a la derecha, se calcular primero
and then is_over_age is going to be assigned to that.
y luego is_over_age se asignar a eso.
And now what this is going to do is it's going
Y ahora, lo que va a hacer
to compare age and 18, and it's going to tell us
es comparar edad y 18 aos, y nos dir si
whether age is greater than or equal to 18.
la edad es mayor o igual a 18.
Now, what do you think is going to be the result
Ahora, cul crees que va a ser el
of this, or rather, what do you think the value
resultado de esto, o mejor dicho,
is going to be for this is_over_age variable?
cul crees que ser el valor para esta variable is_over_age?
I'm sure you got it right.
Estoy seguro de que lo hiciste bien.
Of course, age is greater than or equal to 18,
Por supuesto, la edad es mayor o igual a
so this is a true expression.
18, as que esta es una verdadera expresin.
Indeed, when this runs, it gets replaced by the value True.
De hecho, cuando esto se ejecuta, se reemplaza por el valor True.
And we can check that by quickly printing it out
Y podemos verificarlo imprimindolo rpidamente y
and running our code.
ejecutando nuestro cdigo.
As you can see down here on the right,
Como puede ver aqu abajo, a
it's difficult to see, but True is printed out.
la derecha, es difcil de ver, pero True est impreso.
Of course, we could do is_under_age,
Por supuesto, podramos hacer is_under_age, y eso
and that could be equal to age &lt; 18.
podra ser igual a la edad &lt;18.
Notice how I'm not using less than or equal to 18 here,
Observe que no estoy usando menos de o igual a
because if the age was exactly 18, this would be true,
18 aqu, porque si la edad fuera exactamente 18, esto sera cierto, y
and this would be true, too, which wouldn't make sense.
esto tambin sera cierto, lo cual no tendra sentido.
How can you be overage and underage at the same time?
Cmo puede ser mayor y menor de edad al mismo tiempo?
So of course underage people are those who are 17 and under;
As que, por supuesto, las personas menores de edad son las que tienen 17
that is, less than 18.
aos o menos; es decir, menos de 18.
You could also write this as &lt;= 17,
Tambin podra escribir esto como &lt;= 17, pero creo que
but I think that maybe reads a bit less nicely.
tal vez se lea un poco menos.
It's up to you what you want to do.
Depende de ti lo que quieras hacer.
We can also check whether they are 20 years old,
Tambin podemos verificar si tienen 20
and we can do that by checking age is what?
aos, y podemos hacerlo comprobando la edad es qu?
What do you think we'll be able to do here?
Qu crees que podremos hacer aqu?
A suggestion could be to check whether it is
Una sugerencia podra ser verificar si es mayor o igual
both greater than or equal to 20 and less than 21,
que 20 y menor que 21, pero sera una
but that would be a slightly contrived way of calculating
forma ligeramente artificial de calcular si
whether it is exactly equal to 20.
es exactamente igual a 20.
So instead what we'll do is check whether it is equal to 20.
Entonces, en cambio, lo que haremos es verificar si es igual a 20.
Notice how we've got a single equals sign here.
Observe que tenemos un solo signo igual aqu.
That means that this is going to get calculated,
Eso significa que se calcular y se
and this will be assigned to it,
le asignar, y aqu tenemos
and we've got a double equal sign here,
un doble signo igual, que
which is used for Boolean comparison.
se usa para la comparacin booleana.
It's going to give us true is these two things are the same,
Nos va a dar la verdad es que estas dos cosas son lo
and it's going to give us false if they are not.
mismo, y nos dar falsas si no lo son.
Of course, other symbols are &lt;= and also &gt;.
Por supuesto, otros smbolos son &lt;= y tambin>.
So, you can also use these symbols whenever you want.
Por lo tanto, tambin puede usar estos smbolos siempre que lo desee.
Now, instead of comparing age and 18,
Ahora, en lugar de comparar la edad y los
we could compare age and another variable.
18 aos, podramos comparar la edad y otra variable.
It doesn't have to be a variable compared with a number.
No tiene que ser una variable en comparacin con un nmero.
It can be a variable compared with another variable,
Puede ser una variable en comparacin con otra
or two numbers compared, or two strings compared.
variable, o dos nmeros comparados, o dos cadenas comparadas.
It can be anything you want.
Puede ser lo que quieras.
Anything can go between these symbols here,
Cualquier cosa puede ir entre estos smbolos aqu, pero
but of course what the output will be
por supuesto cul ser el resultado
depends on what you compare.
depende de lo que compares.
Let's have a couple more variables.
Tengamos un par de variables ms.
My_number, which is gonna be five, and a user_number,
My_number, que va a ser cinco, y
which is going to be the input of the user.
un user_number, que ser la entrada del usuario.
Enter a number.
Ingresa un nmero.
Now, let's check whether the number
Ahora, veamos si el nmero
that the user enters is equal to my_number.
que ingresa el usuario es igual a mi_nmero.
Now, we know exactly how we do that by using
Ahora, sabemos exactamente cmo lo hacemos utilizando
the double equal sign, so let's check
el signo doble igual, as que vamos
my_number is exactly equal to user_number.
a verificar que my_number es exactamente igual a user_number.
What do you think will get printed out when we do this?
Qu crees que se imprimir cuando hagamos esto?
Let's run the code.
Vamos a ejecutar el cdigo.
Now we get asked to enter a number,
Ahora nos piden que
and I'm gonna enter four.
ingresemos un nmero, y voy a ingresar cuatro.
What do you think will be output when we do this?
Qu crees que saldr cuando hacemos esto?
I presume you got that right.
Supongo que tienes eso correcto.
False seems a reasonable thing to print out.
Falso parece una cosa razonable de imprimir.
I mean, four is not equal to five, so 5==4 should be false,
Quiero decir, cuatro no es igual a cinco, por lo que 5 == 4 debera ser falso, porque
because they are not the same.
no son lo mismo.
Let's run it again, and this time enter five.
Vamos a ejecutarlo de nuevo, y esta vez ingrese cinco.
But we also get False.
Pero tambin obtenemos False.
But of course you know why that is.
Pero, por supuesto, sabes por qu es eso.
False because this user_number here is a string,
Falso porque este user_number aqu es una cadena, y
and it has to be a number in order for it
tiene que ser un nmero para que
to be able to be compared with five.
se pueda comparar con cinco.
Otherwise, you're comparing apples and oranges.
De lo contrario, ests comparando manzanas y naranjas.
Numbers and strings, don't compare the two,
Nmeros y cuerdas, no compares los
because they're never gonna be equal to one another,
dos, porque nunca sern iguales
even if you think they should be,
entre s, incluso si crees que
because they represent the same thing.
deberan serlo, porque representan lo mismo.
A string and a number, completely different things.
Una cadena y un nmero, cosas completamente diferentes.
You must convert them to the same type
Debe convertirlos al mismo
in order to be able to compare them.
tipo para poder compararlos.
Now notice how here, we've put the int,
Ahora observe cmo aqu, hemos puesto
and inside the brackets, we've put this function here.
el int, y dentro de los corchetes, hemos puesto esta funcin aqu.
Totally fine to do that in Python.
Totalmente bien para hacer eso en Python.
All that happens is whatever's inside the brackets
Todo lo que sucede es que lo que est
is gonna run first.
dentro de los corchetes se ejecutar primero.
So the first thing that runs is this string.
Entonces, lo primero que se ejecuta es esta cadena.
Nothing to do there; it's just a string.
Nada que hacer ahi; es solo una cadena.
Then this runs, because it's inside these brackets,
Entonces esto se ejecuta, porque est dentro de estos corchetes, y luego
and then this runs,
se ejecuta, porque
because it's the last thing that's outside the brackets.
es lo ltimo que est fuera de los corchetes.
At the end, user_number should be equal
Al final, user_number debe ser igual
to the number five, if that's what we enter.
al nmero cinco, si eso es lo que ingresamos.
So let's run this and type that,
Entonces, ejecutemos esto y escriba eso,
and now we get True printed out.
y ahora imprimimos True.
So these two are the same.
Entonces estos dos son lo mismo.
And I'd also like to introduce how to check
Y tambin me gustara presentarles cmo verificar
that they are not the same.
que no sean lo mismo.
We can do that really easily.
Podemos hacer eso realmente fcil.
Instead of ==, I'm gonna use !=.
En lugar de ==, voy a usar! =.
And so that's gonna give us the opposite
Y eso nos dar lo opuesto a
of what this will give us.
lo que esto nos dar.
If this gives us true, this should give us false.
Si esto nos da verdad, esto debera darnos falso.
Let's run that.
Corramos eso.
I'm gonna type five in again, and now you can see
Voy a escribir cinco de nuevo, y ahora
we get True, and then we get False, because this is true.
puedes ver que somos Verdaderos, y luego obtenemos Falso, porque esto es cierto.
They are the same.
Ellos son lo mismo.
This is false.
Esto es falso
Five is not equal to five is not true,
Cinco no es igual a cinco no es cierto,
because they are equal.
porque son iguales.
Okay.
Bueno.
Now, I'd also like to talk to you about combining Booleans.
Ahora, tambin me gustara hablar con usted sobre la combinacin de Booleanos.
For example, imagine you wanna check whether someone
Por ejemplo, imagina que quieres comprobar si alguien
is over 18 and less than 65.
tiene ms de 18 aos y menos de 65.
That's a common thing to do in population censuses.
Eso es algo comn de hacer en los censos de poblacin.
Censuses?
Censos?
Censi.
Censi.
I don't know, in the census, you normally would,
No s, en el censo, normalmente, por
for example, check for something like that.
ejemplo, verifica algo as.
Easy to do that.
Fcil de hacer eso
You do age &gt;= 18, and you just type and.
Tienes edad> = 18, y solo escribes y.
Python is so awesome.
Python es tan increble.
And age &lt; 65.
Y la edad &lt;65.
So you've got these two Booleans here,
As que tienes estos dos booleanos aqu,
and the and just joins them together.
y el y simplemente los une.
So you get this, and you get that,
Entonces entiendes esto, y entiendes eso, y
and of course, is this is true, they are over 18
por supuesto, es cierto, tienen ms de 18 aos
and they are less than 65, if both are true,
y menos de 65, si ambos son ciertos,
the end result is true as well.
el resultado final tambin es cierto.
So let's create a few variables.
Entonces, creemos algunas variables.
True and True.
Verdadero y verdadero
If both things are true beside the and,
Si ambas cosas son verdaderas al lado de y, el
the yes will equal to True.
s ser igual a True.
And of course if True and False,
Y, por supuesto, si es Verdadero y
then no will equal to False,
Falso, entonces no ser igual a Falso,
because this one is true, but this one is not.
porque este es verdadero, pero este no lo es.
In our example of over 18 and under 65,
En nuestro ejemplo de mayores de 18 y menores de 65
this would be that they are not under 65,
aos, esto sera que no tienen menos de 65 aos, por lo
so therefore, it's probably
tanto, probablemente no est dentro
not within that age range that we want.
de ese rango de edad que deseamos.
True and false is always gonna give us false.
Verdadero y falso siempre nos dar falso.
Okay.
Bueno.
Once again, we can check that that's correct
Una vez ms, podemos verificar que eso
by running that and entering five, of course
sea correcto ejecutando eso y ingresando cinco, por supuesto,
because we've still got our Enter a number here,
porque an tenemos nuestro nmero Ingrese aqu,
and then notice how we get false as the third thing in there
y luego notamos cmo obtenemos falso como la tercera cosa
because true and false is always false.
all porque verdadero y falso es siempre falso .
Then we've also got or instead of and.
Entonces tambin tenemos o en lugar de y.
Or is used to and this is a slightly weird way
O est acostumbrado y esta es una forma un poco extraa de
of going about it, and I'm actually gonna write that down,
hacerlo, y realmente voy a escribir eso, solo
just so you've got some text to hang onto when I say this.
para que tengas un texto para colgar cuando digo esto.
And I'm gonna say or is used to get the second value
Y voy a decir o se usa para obtener el segundo valor
if the first one is false.
si el primero es falso.
If the first one is true, it gets the first value, okay?
Si el primero es cierto, obtiene el primer valor, de acuerdo?
Now, this is gonna, this sounds a bit weird,
Ahora, esto va a sonar
but let's ask it a question.
extrao, pero hagmosle una pregunta.
Which_one_is_it = True or False.
Which_one_is_it = Verdadero o Falso.
What value will be given to this variable?
Qu valor le dar a esta variable?
Remember, or is used to get the second value,
Recuerde, o se usa para obtener el segundo
that's this one, if the first one is false.
valor, ese es este, si el primero es falso.
But this one is true.
Pero este es verdad.
If the first one is true, it gets the first value.
Si el primero es verdadero, obtiene el primer valor.
So which one of these two is it gonna be,
Entonces, cul de estos dos va
the first one or the second one?
a ser, el primero o el segundo?
I hope you got that.
Espero que tengas eso.
Because the first value is True,
Como el primer valor es Verdadero,
the or is going to give us the first value.
el o nos dar el primer valor.
So which one is it?
Entonces, cul es?
It's going to be True.
Va a ser cierto.
Feel free by the way to pause this video as we go along
Sintete libre por cierto para pausar este video a medida
and print things out and play around with things.
que avanzamos e imprimir cosas y jugar con las cosas.
That really is the best way to programme.
Esa es realmente la mejor manera de programar.
I'm not gonna stop and waste your time doing that.
No voy a parar y perder tu tiempo haciendo eso.
Of course we wanna be quick.
Por supuesto que queremos ser rpidos.
But nonetheless, the reason why I'm asking you
Pero, no obstante, la razn por la que te
to write this code alongside me is not just so
pido que escribas este cdigo junto a m no es
you're copying it but also so you can play around with it.
solo para que lo copies, sino tambin para que puedas jugar con l.
Similarly, what about this one?
Del mismo modo, qu hay de este?
False or True.
Falso o Verdadero.
Which one will it be?
Cul ser?
Second_one will be assigned what value?
A Second_one se le asignar qu valor?
Again, going by this statement,
De nuevo, siguiendo esta afirmacin, el o se
the or is used to get the second value
usa para obtener el segundo valor
if the first one is false.
si el primero es falso.
The first one here is false,
El primero aqu es
so we get the second one true.
falso, entonces conseguimos que el segundo sea verdadero.
Second, the variable second_one is going to be True.
En segundo lugar, la variable second_one va a ser True.
And of course for the first_one, we'll do something
Y por supuesto para el first_one, haremos algo
that will always give us the first value, True or True.
que siempre nos dar el primer valor, True o True.
No matter whether we would get the first
No importa si obtendramos el
or the second value in this case,
primer o el segundo valor en
we would always have True assigned to this one
este caso, siempre tendremos True asignado a
because there's only that to pick from.
este porque solo hay para elegir.
But of course you know that this here is going to be
Pero, por supuesto, usted sabe que esto
completely ignored because the first value is True.
ser completamente ignorado porque el primer valor es Verdadero.
So we're always gonna get that.
As que siempre vamos a conseguir eso.
Indeed, if you did have a complex mathematical expression
De hecho, si tuviera aqu una expresin matemtica compleja, que
here, which you can do, by the way,
puede hacer, por cierto,
this would not be calculated at all.
esto no se calculara en absoluto.
Python ignores everything because the first one is true.
Python ignora todo porque el primero es verdad.
So why should it calculate anything,
Entonces, por qu debera calcular
if you're always gonna get the first value?
algo si siempre obtendrs el primer valor?
And of course, we've got False or False,
Y, por supuesto, tenemos False
and that's gonna give you neither of them,
o False, y eso no te
or indeed, the second one, False.
dar ninguno de ellos, o de hecho, el segundo, False.
It's not going to be True, but because the first value
No va a ser cierto, pero como el primer valor
is not true, it's gonna give you
no es verdadero, te dar
the second value, which is False.
el segundo valor, que es falso.
Okay.
Bueno.
And so the or is a really interesting construct here,
Y entonces la o es una construccin realmente interesante aqu, una comparacin
a really interesting comparison, and we're gonna be using it
realmente interesante, y la usaremos
a lot more towards the end of the course
mucho ms al final del curso
as you discover some really useful ways of using that.
a medida que descubra algunas formas realmente tiles de usar eso.
Now, let's create another variable which I'm gonna call
Ahora, creemos otra variable que voy a llamar no
not False, and this is another construct that we can use
False, y esta es otra construccin que podemos
for comparing and changing Booleans.
usar para comparar y cambiar Booleanos.
You can probably guess what not False is going to do.
Probablemente puedas adivinar qu va a hacer False.
It's going to give you whatever is not False, which is true.
Te dar lo que no es falso, lo cual es cierto.
So this is going to be True.
Entonces esto va a ser cierto.
And another_no variable is going to be not True,
Y otra variable no va a ser True,
which of course is going to give you False.
lo que por supuesto te dar False.
So, not is going to invert whatever it is that's behind it.
Entonces, no va a invertir lo que sea que est detrs de eso.
So not False is going to give you the opposite of False;
Entonces False no te dar lo opuesto a
not True is going to give you the opposite of True.
False; no Verdadero te dar lo opuesto a Verdadero.
And of course, all of this, all of these or's
Y, por supuesto, todo esto, todo esto o lo que se
and and's and not's can be used with variables as well.
puede y lo que no se puede usar tambin con variables.
You don't have to use them with True and False
No tiene que usarlos con verdadero
or with numbers or anything like that.
y falso ni con nmeros ni nada de eso.
And we can have two variables.
Y podemos tener dos variables.
Is_programmer is True, and is_learning is False.
Is_programmer es True, y is_learning es False.
Not really true, we are learning here.
No es verdad, estamos aprendiendo aqu.
And the awesome is gonna be when we are both a programmer
Y lo asombroso ser cuando ambos somos programadores y
and we are learning, is_programmer and is_learning.
estamos aprendiendo, is_programmer y is_learning.
Okay, so, again, just another example
De acuerdo, entonces, de nuevo, solo otro ejemplo
of using the and here.
de usar el y aqu.
We've got is_programmer, which is True,
Tenemos is_programmer, que es True,
and is_learning, which is False.
e is_learning, que es False.
So awesome is gonna be,
Tan asombroso va a ser,
you got it, it is gonna be False, because the and
lo tienes, va a ser falso, porque el y nos
is gonna give us whether both are true or not.
va a dar si ambos son verdaderos o no.
If either or both are false, it's gonna give us false.
Si alguno o ambos son falsos, nos dar falso.
So, we are gonna be slightly less_awesome
Por lo tanto, vamos a ser
and say is_programmer and not is_learning.
un poco less_awesome y decir is_programmer y no is_learning.
If you're not learning, you're slightly less awesome
Si no ests aprendiendo, eres un poco menos
than if you are learning.
impresionante que si ests aprendiendo.
Of course, thank you for taking this course.
Por supuesto, gracias por tomar este curso.
And also, as a programmer, you're always gonna
Y tambin, como programador, siempre tendr que
have to be learning so that you can continue to develop
estar aprendiendo para poder continuar desarrollando sus
your skills and continue to learn about software.
habilidades y continuar aprendiendo sobre el software.
Software is growing and changing really rapidly,
El software est creciendo y cambiando muy rpido, as que
so if you're not learning,
si no ests aprendiendo,
you're gonna be slightly less awesome over time.
sers un poco menos impresionante con el tiempo.
And of course is_programmer and not is_learning
Y, por supuesto, is_programmer y no
is going to be true, because not is_learning
is_learning va a ser cierto, porque is_learning
is going to evaluate to True,
no va a evaluar True, viendo
seeing how is_learning is False.
cmo is_learning es False.
Not False is gonna give us True,
Not False nos dar True, entonces
so that's True, and True.
eso es Verdadero y Verdadero.
The end result is True, okay?
El resultado final es Verdadero, est bien?
Finally, a slightly more contrived example,
Finalmente, un ejemplo un poco
we're gonna add whether is_designer,
ms artificial, vamos a agregar
and we're gonna say it's False,
si is_designer, y vamos
and we're gonna say that great_guys are those who
a decir que es False, y vamos a decir que great_guys
are either programmers or designers and who are learning.
son aquellos que son programadores o diseadores y que estn aprendiendo.
So, the way to do that is to have the three statements.
Entonces, la forma de hacerlo es tener las tres declaraciones.
Now, I've put some brackets in here to give you
Ahora, he puesto algunos
a hint as to how you might go about grouping
corchetes aqu para darte una pista sobre cmo puedes agrupar estos
these Booleans using brackets, just like maths.
booleanos usando corchetes, al igual que las matemticas.
You can use brackets to group things.
Puedes usar corchetes para agrupar cosas.
So try and create this expression where they must be
As que intente y cree esta expresin
either programmer or designer and learning.
donde deben ser programadores o diseadores y aprender.
So they have to be either programmer or designer,
Entonces tienen que ser programadores o
and they have to be learning.
diseadores, y deben estar aprendiendo.
How would you develop that Boolean?
Cmo desarrollaras ese booleano?
Again, good moment to pause the video and give it a go.
Nuevamente, buen momento para pausar el video y probarlo.
The way I would do it is the first thing we wanna do
La forma en que lo hara es lo primero que
is check whether they're a programmer or a designer.
queremos hacer es comprobar si son programadores o diseadores.
So I would put that inside brackets
As que pondra eso entre
and say is_programmer or is_designer.
corchetes y dira is_programmer o is_designer.
Now, this is going to run first,
Ahora, esto se ejecutar primero, y
and it's going to give us True if either of them is true,
nos dar True si alguno de ellos es verdadero,
and is_learning, and this is going to be the second part
e is_learning, y esta ser la segunda parte fuera de
outside of the brackets so that it runs
los corchetes para que se ejecute despus
after we have evaluated this here.
de que hayamos evaluado esto aqu.
Okay.
Bueno.
Now we've got true and false,
Ahora tenemos verdadero y falso, por
so great_guy is sadly going to be False,
lo que great_guy tristemente va a ser falso, porque no
because we are not learning at the moment.
estamos aprendiendo en este momento.
Of course, we can change that and make ourselves awesome.
Por supuesto, podemos cambiar eso y hacernos impresionantes.
So, let's do it.
Hagamoslo.
Now we can print(great_guy) and we should get True out.
Ahora podemos imprimir (great_guy) y debemos salir con la verdad.
And indeed, down there at the bottom, we get True,
Y de hecho, all abajo, nos hacemos
because we are great.
Verdaderos, porque somos geniales.
So let's move onto the very next video,
Pasemos al siguiente video y
and we're gonna learn a bit more about Python.
aprenderemos un poco ms sobre Python.
I'll see you there.
Te ver all.